好了 莉莉
Okay, Lily.
这单子上有你作业要用的东西
I got the list of what you need for your project.
-荧光胶水 -好的
- Uh, glitter glue... - Okay.
荧光圆片
glitter dots...
荧光纸
glitter...paper.
丹尼尔斯太太说我的作业有太多荧光了
Mrs. Daniels says my projects have too much glitter.
好吧 她需要一个丹尼尔斯先生
Okay, well, she needs a Mr. Daniels,
因为作业再怎么华丽也不为过
because a project can't have too much pizzazz.
这只不过是爱尔兰大饥荒的报告
It's a report on the Potato Famine.
抱歉 难道爱尔兰人的眼泪不会发光吗
I'm -- I'm sorry. Do Irish tears not sparkle?
好吧 抱歉
Okay. Okay. Sorry.
朗吉娜 约坦
Longinus, Jotham.
你们好啊 来干什么呀
Hi, guys. What's up?
没什么 来买点东西
Oh, nothing, just picking up supplies to make signs
-做抗议示威的标语 -对
- for the big protest. - Yes.
对对对 没错
Oh, right. Right, yes.
是什么抗议示威来着...
Uh, uh, w-- and which big protest is --
去回力球酒吧抗议 还用解释吗
We're picketing the Jai Alai Lounge for obvious reasons.
不解释
Obviously.
-不解释 -不解释
- Obviously. - Obviously, yes.
求解释 大爸
What reasons, Daddy?
约坦 你告诉她吧
Um, well, Jotham, y-you tell her.
气得我都不想说了
It makes me so angry, I can't even say it out loud.
烦死人了
So upset.
我们只知道回力球酒吧
All we know is the Jai Alai Lounge
有国内最好吃的汉堡
has the single best burger in the country...
如果不算全宇宙最好吃的话
if not the universe.
-里面有1/4磅安格斯肉眼扒 -是1/3磅
- The Jai Alai Burger is 1/4-pound......Prime Angus, - 1/3.
-新鲜爽脆的生菜 -是牛油生菜
- Uh, fresh, crispy lettuce... - Butter lettuce.
还有从天堂运来的调味酱
a sauce delivered from heaven...
肯萨斯市来的
From Kansas city.
夹在刚出炉完美烤制的圆面包中
all on a perfectly toasted, fresh-baked bun.
上面还洒了芝麻
With sesame seeds.
我都想拿来做我的婚礼蛋糕了
I wanted to have it as our wedding cake.
下一个婚礼上用吧
Maybe for your next one.
都有谁要去抗议呢
So, who's this "we" that's picketing?
每周我们都会有一群人集合起来
Every week, a group of us get together
去抗议那些阻碍同性恋事业发展的人
to protest those who have been holding back the gay cause.
为什么没有邀请我们
Why haven't we ever been invited?
因为你们两个不是那么...
It's just that you're not that...
关心政治
political.
就是自从...
Uh, um, you know, ever since...
他知道我看得到吧
He knows I can see, right?
我们非常非常关心政治
We are very, very political people.
对啊 我们刚刚还在讨论...
Yes, we were just discussing...
-爱尔兰土豆饥荒呢 -对
- the Potato Famine of Ireland. - Yes.
我都四年没吃过土豆了
I haven't had a potato in four years.
如果你们真的感兴趣
Well, if you're honestly interested,
我们这周六中午会去那边
we'll be out there on Saturday at noon.
你们也来吧
You should come join us.
-我们会的 -对 带着铃铛去
- We will. - Yep. With bells.
-对 那只是一种比喻 -天呐
- Yeah. That's just -- that's an expression. - Oh, gosh.
其实是莉莉土豆饥荒的作业要用的
These are for Lily's project on the Potato Famine, actually.
-好吧 再见 -好吧
- Oh, okay. Bye. - Well, all right.
-回见 伙计们 -再见
- See ya, Guys. - Bye.
周六见 伙计们
See ya Saturday, guys.
是啊 很高兴见到你 再见
Yeah, good to see you. Bye.
天呐 这你能信吗
Oh, my god. Can you believe that?
对啊 对于一个
Yeah, he's a little hippy
不吃土豆的人来说 他也太嬉皮了吧
for somebody that doesn't eat potatoes.
就在艾丽克斯毕业一周前
We were called into Principal Brown's office
我们被请到布朗校长的办公室
one week before Alex's graduation.
这只有两种可能
That can mean only one of two things.
要么艾丽克斯要做学生代表致告别辞
Either she's gonna be valedictorian
要么他们要给最性感爸爸颁奖了
or they're giving an award for sexiest dad.
我们为艾丽克斯感到骄傲
We're very proud of Alex.
亲爱的
Honey.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我只是觉得我这辈子的努力
I just feel like my whole life
一直都是为了这一刻
has been building up to this point.
我知道
I know.
你们好啊 邓菲们
Hello, Dunphys.
能在繁多的会面中
So nice to be able to
告诉你们一则好消息 真是太好了
give you some good news in one of these meetings.
顺便问一句 海莉好吗
How is Haley, by the way?
很抱歉我们迟到了 我们
So sorry we're late. We --
-她来这里干什么 -他来这里干什么
- What's she doing here? - What's he doing here?
艾丽克斯和桑杰
Well, Alex and Sanjay,
在四年的激烈竞争之后
after four years of spirited competition,
我很高兴地告诉你们
I am very pleased to tell you
你们两个将成为巴利高中2015届的
that you are the Pali High class of 2015 --
联合学生代表
co-valedictorians!
太棒了 太棒了
That's amazing! Yes!
太为你们感到骄傲了
Couldn't be more proud of the both of you, huh?
你说联合学生代表是什么意思
What do you mean -- co-valedictorians?
"联合"是拉丁语前缀表意"一起"
"Co" is the latin prefix for "together."
但说真的 联合学生代表是什么意思
But really, what do you mean -- co-valedictorians?
我料到可能会碰到一些令我紧张的质问
Well, I thought there might be some aggressive questions
所以我把我的回答提前写下来了
that, uh, made me nervous, and so I wrote down my remarks.
不 我不是要毁掉你们的人生
No, I'm not trying to ruin your lives.
只是因为你们两个的绩点持平
It's just that your GPAs are tied
小数点后一千位也是一样的
to the thousandth of a decimal point.
-但我的绩点是4.645923 -我的绩点是4.645923
- But my GPA'S 4.645923. - My GPA's 4.645923.
她法语期末考只得了个A-
She got an "A-" On the French final.
他的一篇英语论文只得了A-
He got an "A-" on an English paper.
不
No.
这简直是噩梦
This is a nightmare.
这辈子最糟糕的一天
Worst day of my life.
各位 我们该庆祝一番
Guys, we should be celebrating.
这是真正意义上的双赢
This is literally a win/win.
我这辈子这么努力可不是为了平局
I didn't work my whole life for a tie.
无意冒犯 校长 但你是学教育学的
No offense, Principal Brown, but you were a teaching major.
我想自己核算一下绩点
I'd like to check the GPAs myself.
请便
Have at it.
这俩人怎么了啊
What is it with these two?
我同意他们 平局不是美国风格
I agree with them. Ties are un-American.
如果超级碗最后平局了 你会高兴吗
Would you be happy if the Super Bowl ended in a tie?
会啊 会有两次夺冠游行
Yes! There'd be twice as many parades!
肯定有办法决定
There must be some way to determine
最棒的学生是谁
who the best student is.
不幸的是
Well, unfortunately,
所有期末考试和论文都结了
all the final exams and the papers are in.
分数已经算完了
Grades are closed.
可不是所有分数哦
Not all the grades.
看来管理员终于修好了我的椅子
Looks like the janitor finally fixed my chair.
你们来这里干什么呢
What are you guys all doing here?
最后加入联邦的是哪两个州
What are the last two states to be admitted into the union?
阿拉斯加和夏威夷
Alaska and Hawaii.
列举两个内阁职位[橱柜位置]
Name two cabinet-level positions.
很简单
That's easy.
上面一层是放杯子的
There's a higher one for the glasses
下面一层是放锅碗瓢盆的
and a lower one for the pots and the pans.
别骄傲
Hey, don't get cocky.
我们开始准备时
When we started studying for this,
你还以为国防部长的工作
you thought the secretary of defense job
是保卫"栅栏"
was to guard "da fence."
歌洛莉亚要参加公民入籍测试了
Gloria's about to take her citizenship test.
这个小跳豆要成为美国人了
This little jumping bean's about to become an American.
跳豆是墨西哥的
Jumping beans are Mexican.
等你成了美国人就看不出区别了
Once you're an American, you won't see the difference.
我给你准备了一份庆祝礼物
I got you a little gift to celebrate.
我知道这不算什么
I know it's not much.
简直就是什么都不算
It's practically nothing.
这很美式 很有趣
It's America. It's fun.
谢谢 杰 我好激动
Aww, thank you, Jay. I'm so excited.
你知道我通过以后就可以担任陪审员了吗
Do you know that once I pass, I can serve on a jury?
他们还用电椅 对吧
They still use the electric chair, right?
我们回来了
We're back.
好啊 哈维尔
Hola, Javier.
"带孩子不上班日"怎么样
How was "take your son to not work" day?
收音机发明前生活怎么样
How was life before radio?
曼尼和我说了你打算
Manny told me about your plans
抛弃哥伦比亚之根
to abandon your Colombian roots.
真的吗 就你还有脸跟我聊抛弃
Really? You're gonna lecture me on abandonment?
当初你说出门买尿布
You left to buy some diapers,
结果我四年后才看到你
and I saw you four years later.
如果你能像放弃故乡一样忘掉那事就好了
If only you could let that go as easily as your homeland.
他们是在吵架还是重新坠入爱河
Are they fighting or falling back in love?
牛
c-cow!
Cow?
牛
Cow?!
要抛弃自己国家的女人
The woman who is abandoning her country
连西班牙语的"牛"都不知道怎么说了
cannot remember the Spanish word for cow.
脑子刚没转过来
It slipped my mind.
牛
Vaca.
我办公室外面有个墨西哥玉米卷餐车
There'a taco truck parked outside my office.
看来你俩的体育成绩一样
Well, it looks like you both have the same gym grade,
但我发现你们
but I do see here that neither of you
都没完成这学期的一英里跑
have completed this semester's mile run.
我们当时在参加辩论比赛
We were at a debate tournament.
-我们赢了 多亏了我 -得了吧
- Which we won, thanks to me. - Oh, please.
你对安乐死进行冗长总结时
After your long-winded summation on euthanasia,
人们都想自杀了
people wanted to kill themselves.
够了 我们让你们补考
Enough. We will do a makeup race.
谁赢了就可以做学生代表
And whoever wins gets to be valedictorian.
放马过来吧
You're on.
这太疯狂了 你们如此执念于做第一名
This is crazy. Are we all so obsessed with being number one
搞得我们现在都不能庆祝了
that we can't just celebrate this moment?
是啊 他们不仅高中毕业
Yeah, I mean, it's the end of their senior year.
还都进了很棒的大学
They're both into great colleges.
他们该去庆祝 逃学
They should be off celebrating, playing hookey,
去湖边跟朋友的
going up to the lake house to go skinny-dipping
从大学回来的帅哥去裸泳
with their friend's older brother who's home from college.
-别说得太具体了 克莱尔 -好吧
- Let's -- let's keep this general, Claire. - Okay. Yeah.
重点是 这两个孩子都很棒
The point is these are two amazing kids.
我们该为他们庆祝
We should be celebrating them both.
你这么想我们不感到意外
Mm, we're not surprised you would think that.
很好
Great.
等等 什么
Wait. What?
每个家长都想相信
Every parent wants to believe
他们的孩子能和桑杰一较高下
that their child can compete with Sanjay.
艾丽克斯的确能和桑杰一较高下
But Alex can compete with Sanjay.
不然我们在这里干什么
That's why we're here.
桑杰13个月时就会说完整的句子了
Sanjay was forming full sentences at 13 months.
艾丽克斯5岁时就在《聚焦》杂志上
Alex had a poem published in Highlights magazine
发表了诗歌
when she was 5 years old.
诗的名字是《绵羊先生买火腿》[相煎何太急]
It was called "Mr. Lamb Buys a Ham."
但其实讲的是大屠杀
But really, it was about the holocaust.
桑杰16岁时
When he was 16,
是州里排名第一的国际象棋手
Sanjay was the highest-ranked chess player in the state.
艾丽克斯15岁时
When Alex was 15,
她发现了我们报税的一个错误
she discovered a mistake in our taxes.
我们差点少交了好多税
We owed a lot more money than I realized.
就艾丽克斯这种背景而言
Yes, we're very impressed with how much Alex
她能有这种成就我们也感到很惊讶
has been able to accomplish, given her background.
好吧 你说得没错
You know what? You're right.
我们在赛道上了解这件事吧
Let's settle this out on the track.
好了 塔克教练
All right, coach Tucker,
我们应该可以指望你的公正性吧
I'm assuming we can count on you to officiate.
通常情况下
Well, now, normally,
我不喜欢成为人群的焦点
I don't like to be the center of attention.
没关系 我可以找别人
That's fine. I'll get someone else.
我说了我可以
I said I would do it.
艾丽克斯的舅舅是不可能公正裁判的
Alex's uncle cannot possibly be considered an impartial judge.
我是体育老师
I'm the gym teacher.
还有谁有能力来作出判断吗
Who else has the training to oversee this?
只要有秒表就行了吧
Anyone with a stopwatch?
我告诉你 别侮辱我
Okay, you know what? No need to humiliate me.
希望最棒的孩子赢
May the best child win.
她会的
Oh, she will.
我们定会"刃不血兵"
Consider this moment gauntleted.
有这成语吗
Is that a word?
你就装作它是吧
Hold your head up like it is.
只要肯信 万物成真
Vocabulary's mostly a matter of confidence.
很高兴我们能参与进来
I love that we're getting involved.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
我觉得我们的示威标语能够震慑住
I think we're really gonna send a strong message to whomever
任何人 不管他做了什么坏事
to stop doing whatever it is he or she is doing.
"耻辱"也可以震慑住上千种不同的事情
Oh, like "shame" doesn't cover 1,000 different things?
好吧 大家在哪里
Okay. Where is everybody?
基佬的话果然不靠谱
So like the gays to no-show.
是吧
Yeah, right?
是巴尼斯现在打折却没人告诉我们吗
Is there a sale at Barney's that nobody told us about?
-你说真的吗 -我不知道
- Seriously, is there? - I don't know.
朗吉娜和约坦总是这样
Longinus and Jotham do this all the time.
他们靠罪恶感让我们干个什么事
They -- they guilt us into doing something,
结果自己却跑了
and then they bail.
他们在胡娇家的新年史蒂夫派对上也是这样
They did it at Pepper's New Year's Steve party.
所有人都要穿成某个著名史蒂夫的样子
Yeah, everybody had to dress as a famous Steve.
史蒂夫·奥斯汀[摔跤手]
Steve Austin.
史蒂夫·马丁[演员]
Steve Martin.
他们没来
They bailed,
我们被困在一屋子桑德海姆里[音乐剧作家]
and we got stuck in a room full of Sondheims.
你怎么样
How are you doing?
我叫史蒂夫
My name is Steve.
打扰你下
Hi. Excuse me.
-两个人吗 -不 不是的
- Table for two? - No, no. God no.
今天下午你们门口来过抗议者吗
Have there been any protesters out front this afternoon?
那些基佬吗 今天没有
Oh, the gay thing? Not today.
想都不用想
Oh, of course.
我们忙了一个早上
We rush around all morning --
我连早餐都没吃 结果白费了
I haven't eaten breakfast -- and -- and for nothing.
这里的味道闻起来真棒
And it couldn't smell any better in here.
我们有一张空桌子
We do have a table.
不 谢谢
No, thank you.
不行 我们不能仅仅为了食物放弃信念
No, we're not gonna compromise our principles just for...
我们可以坐在不靠窗户的位置
We'll take a booth away from the window.
后面可以 后面有位置吗
In back. Something in back?
-这边请 -好的
- This way. - Okay.
天呐 她还在跑
Oh, my God. She's still going.
就是啊
I know.
还记得她三年级的时候
Remember how winded she used to get
穿尤利西斯戏服走有多喘吗
hauling around "Ulysses" in the third grade?
她那么不协调居然能跑得如此优雅
She's surprisingly graceful for being so uncoordinated.
就是啊 我想拍她摔倒的搞笑画面
I know. I was hoping to get a funny video of her falling.
我觉得是拍不到了
But I don't think it's gonna happen.
我的歌两分钟前就放完了 我都听到了
My playlist ended two minutes ago. I heard all that.
亲爱的 我知道我们以前就这么说过
Honey, I know we were all just saying it before,
但你说不定真能赢的
but you could actually win this thing.
我不只是说 我说到做到
I wasn't just saying it. I will win.
没有什么能...
Nothing is going to...
终于拍到了
Oh. There it is.
发生什么事了
What's going on here?
我在做蔬菜肉块汤
I'm making sancocho.
边做还边听着哥伦比亚音乐
Yeah. You got your little Colombian music going, huh?
我知道 很好听
I know. So beautiful.
你很在意哈维尔的话 对吧
Javier got to you, didn't he?
没
No.
可能有一点点
Maybe a little bit.
歌洛莉亚 别听他的 把那锅炖松鼠倒了
Gloria, don't listen to him. Get rid of that squirrel stew.
我买了些庆祝你
I got a few special things here
成为美国人的东西
to help celebrate you becoming an American.
你瞧 神户牛排[日本产]
Look. Kobe steaks.
一瓶威士忌[苏格兰产]
Bottle of scotch.
雪茄[古巴产]
Cigars.
要知道这些都不是美国产的
You know that none of that is made in America.
但是把它们都买下来是美国人做的
Buying them all was the American part.
杰 我没心情
Jay, I'm not in the mood.
-我有些困惑 -好吧
- I am having some doubts. - Okay.
你听了哈维尔的话 现在该听我的了
You listened to Javier. Now listen to me.
你知道我为什么想让你成为美国人吗
Do you know why I want you to become an American citizen?
因为我曾为这个国家战斗过
Because I fought for this country.
我父亲也为这国家战斗过
My father fought for this country.
因为这个国度一向坚持自由和平等
Because this country's all about freedom and opportunity,
我希望你能完整地感受这些
And I want you to share in that 100%.
你说得对 那也是我想要的
You're right. I want that, too.
抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你只是有点怕吧
Hey, you're just a little scared.
我知道什么能让你好过一点
I know what will help you feel better.
我们把牛排一烤 美酒一倒
We'll fire up some steaks, we'll pour a little wine,
你把那条热裤一穿
you pop into those short shorts,
我在客厅和你追逐打闹
I chase you around the living room --
就那事儿 你懂的
that type of thing.
妈妈
Hey, mom.
今晚我朋友比利
Um, I got invited
请我去他家吃晚餐
to my friend Billy's house for dinner tonight.
别担心 我们不会吃这个的
Don't worry. We're not gonna eat this.
我们吃牛排
We're gonna eat steak.
太好了 其实没有比利这个人
Oh, good. There's no Billy.
为什么突然变菜单了
Why the sudden change in menu?
我本来有些困惑 但杰帮我解开了
Well, I was having some doubts, but Jay made me feel better.
他告诉了我他希望我成为美国人的原因
He told me the reason why he wants me to be an American.
排队那事啊
Oh, those long lines.
-排什么队 -过海关排长队
- What long lines? - The customs line.
杰讨厌每次从卡波回来都要排长队
Oh, Jay hates them when we come back from Cabo.
什么
What?
那个王八蛋想要我背叛我的祖国
That son of a bitch wants me to turn my back on my homeland
就为了在机场不排队
for an airport line?
我至少得去比利家露个脸
You know, I should at least make an appearance at Billy's.
桑杰 你来这里干什么
Sanjay. What are you doing here?
那是什么
What are those?
踝部负重袋
Ankle weights.
其实是腕部负重袋
Okay. Wrist weights.
你来干什么
Why are you here?
听着 明天一切就要结束了
Look, uh, tomorrow, it's all gonna be over,
入学以来我们为之努力的一切都要结束了
everything we've been working for since we started school.
所以 我想来谢谢你
So, I-I wanted to come by and say thanks.
我还不是个医生
I'm not a doctor yet,
但我能看出你的脑子好像出了问题
but it seems like you're having some sort of brain episode.
不 我是认真的 谢谢你一直激励我
No, I'm serious. Thank you for pushing me.
你知道一生都追赶你有多难吗
You know how hard it's been to keep up with you my whole life?
多亏了你我才能得到这个绩点
Uh, I have my GPA because of you.
多亏了你我才能被斯坦福录取
I got into Stanford because of you.
我得承认我为了超过你
I'll admit I did spend about a few hundred extra hours
确实多花了几百个小时
trying to be better than you.
上大学后我会怀念这一切的
I'm gonna miss this when we go to college.
是啊 我觉得我也会怀念的
Yeah, I guess I'll miss this, too.
我喜欢你
I like you.
好吧
Okay.
我说的是那种喜欢
I mean like-like,
像皮埃尔·居里喜欢玛丽·居里一样
like how Pierre Curie liked Marie Curie.
对不起 我说得太过火了
I'm sorry. I-I went too far.
你身上真好闻 我得走了
You smell pretty. I should go.
艾丽克斯去哪儿了 我给她做了奶昔
Where's Alex? I made her a smoothie.
可能原料有点太健康了
Might have made it a little too healthy.
为什么我们只专注于帮艾丽克斯赢
Why are we so focused on helping Alex win
而没有致力于让桑杰输
when we could be working on making Sanjay lose?
-继续说 -跑道上有窨井吗
- Talk to me. - Okay, is there a manhole on the track,
因为那对我的计划至关重要
cause it's kind of important to my plan.
好吧 有件奇怪的事 桑杰刚刚来了
Okay, that was weird. Sanjay was just here.
他说我们的竞争是他高中时期
He said that the best part of high school
最美好的一段 还有...
was our competition, and...
他喜欢我
that he liked me.
甜心
Oh, honey.
怎么了
What?
这个时机选得有些可疑吧
Doesn't the timing seem a little suspicious to you?
也许是 但他看上去很真诚
Maybe, but he seemed really genuine.
典型的心理战
Classic psychological warfare.
我在精英竞争中见到过
I've dealt with it in elite competitions.
我不知道这种事在拉拉队以外也会发生
I didn't realize it happened outside of cheerleading.
仔细想想 亲爱的
Think about it, sweetie.
他以前对你说过好听的吗
Has he ever said anything nice to you before?
没有
No.
我亮出幽默上衣的时候都没有
Not even when I break out my fun blazer.
我的天呐 我怎么了
Oh, my god. What is wrong with me?
我不敢相信我居然让他扰乱了我的思绪
I can't believe I let him get in my head.
他死定了
Oh, he is going down.
明天起桑杰·帕特尔一生都得屈居第二了
Tomorrow, Sanjay Patel begins a lifetime of second best.
享受你的氢牌饼干[类似奥利奥]
Enjoy your Hydrox cookies
和银牌吧 副总统先生
and your silver medal, Mr. Vice President!
加油 姑娘
You go, girl.
我们有饼干吗
Do we have any cookies?
歌洛莉亚
Gloria.
你好啊 老公
Howdy, hubby.
在我们开足马力前先吃点零食如何
How about some grub before we turn on the nascar?
说实话 我挺喜欢事情的走向
I'm not gonna lie, I like where this is going.
但是 我不确定自己该不该喜欢
But, uh...i'm not sure I'm supposed to.
这不就是你想要的吗
Ain't this what you wanted?
一个完美的美国妻子
The perfect American wife
让你的生活更加便利
to make your life more convenient?
你觉得这是美国口音吗
Do you think that's an American accent?
德州口音
From Texas.
曼尼告诉我你想让我放弃我的传统
Manny told me that you want me to give up my heritage
这样你就不用在机场排队了
so that you don't have to wait in line at the airport.
我不能再在喝醉后和那孩子聊天了
Oh, I got to stop talking to that kid when I'm drinking.
我不去考试了
Well, I'm not gonna do it.
和你的美国小娇妻告别吧
So say goodbye to your little American wife.
天呐 那条热裤真能让我
Man, those shorts really take the sting
忘了被骂的痛
out of getting yelled at.
我的天呐 那个汉堡太棒了
Oh, my God, that burger was so good,
我感觉就像劈腿了似的
I feel like I just cheated on you.
我听见你的呻吟了 我们是不是很差劲
Yeah, I heard the moaning. Are we terrible people?
我觉得不是 听我说
I don't think we are. Look, hear -- hear me out.
我们吃了那些汉堡就避免了
By eating those burgers, we denied them
让它们被那些可能来这家餐厅的
from the sort of narrow-minded homophobes
恐同者享受的可能性
that would come to a restaurant like this.
好吧 我没太懂 但我喜欢你的结论
Okay, I don't totally follow, but I like where you ended up.
我意思就是我们来这里是正确的选择
I-I'm just saying that we did the right thing by coming here,
天呐 基友
And I feel like -- oh, god, gays.
我们在这 我们是基友
We're here! We're queer!
我们不支持为不支持同志享有伴侣医保的
We don't support corporations that contribute to Super PACs
超级政治行动委员会捐款的企业
which don't support healthcare coverage for same-sex partners!
原来如此
Oh, right.
原来是为这个进行抵制啊
Right. That's why we're boycotting this place.
原来如此
Right.
我们在这 我们是基友
We're here! We're queer!
我们该怎么悄悄混进去
How are we supposed to fall in without them noticing?
就跟跳双摇大绳一样
Okay, it's just like double dutch.
找准节奏跳进去就行 快快
Just find the rhythm and jump in. Go, go.
-现在 -对
- Right now? - Yeah.
我们在这 我们是基友
We're here! We're queer!
我们不支持为不支持同志享有伴侣医保的
We don't support corporations thatontribute to Super PACs
超级政治行动委员会捐款的企业
which don't support healthcare corage for same-sex partners!
我们在这 我们是基友
We're here! We're queer!
我们不支持为不支持同志享有伴侣医保的
We don't support corporations that contribute to Super PACs
超级政治行动...
which don't support...
你们来了呢
Hey, you came!
真是出人所料呢
Well, well, well. What a surprise.
有这什么好意外的
I don't know why this is a surprise.
我们很关心政治
We're very political people.
对啊 我们每一天都在热切地
Yes, there's not a week that goes by that we're not
关心着基佬社会面临的问题
deeply entrenched in the issues that face our community.
热切 那是相当热切
Deeply. Deeply.
-还有这个超级政治行动委员会 -委员会
- And this whole, um, Super PAC thing... - Super PAC.
真是太让人气愤了
It's -- it is infuriating.
普里契特先生 您把手机落下了
Mr. Pritchett, you forgot your cellphone inside.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
你们来之前
See, uh, before you guys got here,
我们走进这家餐厅
we went in there,
让他们退礼物卡的钱
and we demanded a refund for our gift cards.
-我们深入虎穴 -没错
- Yes, we went into the belly of the beast. - So...yes, we did.
-先生 您忘拿打包的菜了 -谢谢
- Sir, you forgot your food to go. - Thank you.
-深入虎穴吃饭吗 -不要脸
- And fed your bellies. - How could you?
得了吧 别一副高高在上的样子
Okay, before you get all superior,
我们早餐以后啥都没吃
We hadn't eaten since breakfast.
现在才12:45好嘛
It's a quarter to 1:00.
对啊已经12:45了
That's what I'm saying.
听我说 没错
Okay, you know what? Yes.
我们一身正气地走进去
We went in there with the best of intentions,
我们是没忍住 可在场的谁没有过啊
and we stumbled, but who amongst us hasn't?
-这不就是我们现在争取的吗 -对啊
- And, okay, isn't that what we're fighting for -- - yes.
争取做不完美的人
the freedom to fall short of perfection
而依旧被等同视之的权利
and still be judged by the same standard as everyone else?
-对吧 -谢谢
- That. - Thank you.
不是
No.
你没听到口号吗 我们抗议的不是这事
Didn't you hear our chant? It was really quite clear.
-口号太长了 -听着
- It's quite long. - You know, look.
-我们想担起社会责任 -没错
- We want to be socially responsible. - We do.
我们想做正确的事
We want to do the right thing.
-但要记得清... -太难了
- But it's hard to keep track... - So hard.
所有我们该喜欢的公司
of all the companies that we like
-和不该喜欢的公司太难了 -不该喜欢的
- and that we don't like. - Don't like.
我们就想适应这个世界
We're -- we're just trying to make it in this world,
抚养女儿 让她进足球队
raise our daughter, get her to her soccer game.
你说的该不会是少年足球协会
Not Youth Soccer Federation.
因为如果你说的是少年足球协会
'Cause if it's Youth Soccer Federation --
-我不想知道 -我了个娘啊
- I don't want to know. - Oh, my God!
耻辱 耻辱
You know what? Sh-shame! Shame!
耻辱 奇耻大辱
Shame! Shame on you.
你们比那餐厅里的人好不到哪去
You are no better than the people in that restaurant.
小卡 走了
Come on, Cam let's go.
走
Come on.
他们被唬住了吗
Think they bought it?
抬头 别往后看
Keep your head up. Don't look back.
只要肯信 万物成真
Being right is mostly confidence.
好了 是我不对
Okay, look. I'm sorry.
我们没事了吧
We good?
明显没有
Apparently not.
拿在机场排队当借口
Look, complaining about a line at an airport
比承认真实的原因要容易
is easier than admitting the truth about why I want you to become a citizen.
我想我还是很不爽
I guess it still bothers me
你和哈维尔之间千丝万缕的联系
that you have all these ties to Javier.
什么联系 你瞎扯些什么
What ties? What are you talking about?
歌洛莉亚·迪尔加多-普里契特
Gloria Delgado-Pritchett.
你还留着他的姓 你们都是哥伦比亚人
You still have his last name. You're both Colombians.
我们回国的时候
When you and I come back to the country,
得排不同的队
we have to wait in separate lines
就像我们不是一家人
like we're not even in the same family.
我也不知道
I don't know.
我猜如果你加入美国籍
I guess I just thought that if you committed to America,
你可能就完全属于我了
in some weird way, you'd be recommitting to me.
你从没安静过这么长时间
That's the longest you've ever been quiet,
好吓人
And it's terrifying.
我知道没人问我意见
I know nobody asked for my advice --
那你还说些什么
Yet you're talking..
我同意杰
I agree with Jay.
听他说
Let's hear him out.
妈 别为了他加入美国籍
Don't do this for him, mom.
你怎么这么多话
You're all over the place.
你也不该在意爸爸的想法
But you also shouldn't worry about what Dad thinks.
我觉得你应该加入美国籍
I think you should become a citizen
是因为我们还住在旧公寓的时候
because even back when we were alone in our apartment,
这就是你想要的
this is what you always wanted.
还记得我们坐在窗边
Remember sitting by the window,
看邻居电视里的《迈阿密风云》重播吗
watching reruns of "Miami Vice" on the neighbor's TV,
所有的坏人都被抓住了
and all the bad guys were caught
所有警察都开着那些好车
and all the policemen had those -- those nice cars?
我们看的时候就想
We used to watch that
这国家真美好
and think what an amazing country this was.
我调查了一下
Did a little research.
如果杰去享"极乐"之后
If mom isn't a citizen when Jay
妈妈还不是正式公民
"moves on to a better place",
遗产税的数字就要吓死人了
we could be looking at a pretty hefty estate tax.
我不想让人觉得我没人性
I don't want to sound insensitive,
可我实在不能忍受吃不上松露的日子
but I have acquired a real taste for truffles.
好了 孩子们 一共四圈
All right, kids, four laps.
先跑完的人获胜
First one to finish wins.
不是什么高数大物 不过对你们来说
It's not rocket science, unfortunately for you,
高数可能反倒更容易
because I think you'd find that easier.
紧张吗
You nervous?
加油 艾丽克斯 你能行
Come on, Alex! You can do it!
你出生的那天早上我跑了六英里
I ran six miles the morning you were born!
你出娘胎就准备好了
You came out of the womb ready for this!
桑杰 你的115个表亲都支持你
Sanjay! Your 115 cousins are rooting for you!
你为什么不理我
Why are you ignoring me?
好了 各就各位
All right, on your mark.
听我说 昨天我没想要吓到你
Look. I didn't mean to weird you out yesterday.
别说了 我才不会上这些心理战术的当
Stop it. I'm not falling for these little mind games.
-预备 -那不是心理战术
- Get set. - It's not a game.
是我的真实想法
It's how I feel.
我说了打住 桑杰
I said enough, Sanjay.
快跑 桑杰
Run, Sanjay!
怎么回事
What's happening?
他肯定知道什么我们不知道的事
He must know something we don't.
别跑了 艾丽克斯 这是个陷阱
Stop running, Alex! It's a trap!
你干吗呢
What are you doing?
昨天我说的是实话
I was telling the truth yesterday.
如果能证明我真的喜欢你
I don't care if I lose valedictorian
我不在乎丢掉致告别辞的机会
if it'll prove that I really like you.
你是认真的吗
Are -- are you serious?
是的
Yes.
请不要笑我
Please don't laugh at me.
露着细腿我觉得好尴尬
I'm -- I'm feeling very exposed with my skinny legs.
我喜欢你的腿
I-I like your legs.
真的
You do?
我喜欢你的头发
Well... I love your hair.
还有你的微笑
And your smile.
还有别人答错题时
And the way you roll your beautiful brown eyes
你漂亮的棕色眼睛翻白的样子
when someone gets an answer wrong.
我搞不懂怎么回事
I don't understand what's going on.
他为什么不跑
Why isn't he running?
我们花了1200元在Skype上了一节博尔特的课呢
We spent $1,200 on a Skype session with Usain Bolt.
感觉我们该接吻了
Uh, I feel like we're about to kiss.
我们该接吻了吗 我还没真的
Are we about to kiss, 'cause I've never really --
我的天 他们在接吻
Oh, my god. They're kissing.
桑杰 你在干什么
Sanjay! What are you doing?!
离她远点
Get away from her!
好萌啊
Oh, it's so cute.
他看上去挺在行的
He seems quite skilled at it.
行了 就这样吧
Okay, that's enough.
我觉得 可以低调点
I-I think -- I think we can dial it back.
那么就一起做联合学生代表吧
So, co-valedictorians it is.
为了这比赛我错过了家得宝的瓷砖展示会
I missed a tile demo at home depot for this,
你们俩倒好
but good for you.
这片土地上
This is a land
生活着众多不同文化背景的人
where people of vastly different cultures
他们因奋斗的意愿和对成功的渴望
are brought together by their willingness to work hard
汇集在一起
and their desire to succeed.
我的吻技比你好
I'm a better kisser than you are.
开玩笑 姐分分钟碾压你
You're joking, right? I'm actually destroying you.
这片土地
This is a land made great
因坚持信仰的人们而伟大
by people standing up for what they believe.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我说啊
Um, you know what?
我决定 我们不能吃这盒扭扭薯条
I have decided that we -- we cannot eat these curly fries.
摇一摇
Ba-ba-ba! Shake it.
摇盒子 小卡
The container, Cam.
这是自由的灯塔
This is a beacon of freedom.
欢迎来到美利坚合众国
Welcome to the United States of America.
她是你老婆
That's your wife?
这国家很不错 对吧
Pretty great country, huh?
准备好了吗
Okay. You ready to begin?
准备好了
Yes.
美国政府有几个分支
The United States government has how many branches?
-三个 -正确
- Three. - Correct.
美国国旗上的星星是什么颜色的
What color are the stars on the American flag?
白的 不过我觉得我有义务告诉你
White, but I feel like it's my duty to tell you
你背后就有面国旗
that you have a flag right behind you,
我觉得你该换个问题问我
so probably you need to ask me another question.
不用了 恭喜你 你通过了
No need. Congratulations, you passed.
什么 没了吗 才两个问题
What? That's it? Two questions?
还有作弊旗 这样就行了吗
And I have a cheat flag? That's all it takes?
对 你会收到官方信函
Yep, you'll get an official letter in the mail
里面有你宣誓仪式的细节
with the details of your oath ceremony.
你知道我为此花了多长时间学习吗
Do you know how long I've been studying for this?
你把我的成就感都剥夺了
You're robbing me of the feeling of achievement.
再问我一个问题 要难点的
Ask me another question, and a hard one this time.
-可你已经通过了 -快点
- But you already passed -- - Do it.
好吧
Okay.
国会有几个成员
How many Congress members are there?
问迟了 你都说了我已经过了
You know what? It's too late. You've already said that I passed.